

# ROMAIN GIOUX

# Web Developer

Always setting new goals and seeking ambitious challenges. Ready to craft interactive web environement and to solve digital puzzles.



romaingioux.dev



romaingiouxdev@gmail.com



+33 698 117 167



github.com/nordend4000



linkedin.com/in/romain-gioux



59 drusbergstrasse 8053 Zürich, Switzerland



Work & Residency: B Permit

### LAST POSITION

**Project Management Officer** Disability Support Worker

Tea Cup Cottage - Capalaba, Australia MAY 2018 - JUNE 2020

Within the Blue Tongue Adventure program, the project was to open a cafe and a shared garden to provide professional training for young adults with a disability.

- Researched a new premise.
- Scheduled and supervised works to adapt the space.
- Implemented safety regulations and risk policies.
- Logistic coordination to run activities and training for clients.

### LANGUAGES

French English Spanish

German



## TECHNICAL SKILLS



#### **FRONT END:**

JavaScript / React / SEO HTML / CSS / SASS / SVG Responsive / Bootstrap GSAP / Cypress / Jest



#### **BACK END:**

Node.js / Mongo DB / SQL Firebase / Netlify / Heroku



#### CROSSOVER:

VS Code / Git / NPM CompasMongoDB / Dev Tools MySQLworkbench / FTP WordPress / Shopify Mac OS / Windows Figma / Photoshop AutoCAD / Sketchup

### FEATURED PROJECTS

#### E-commerce Website

View Store

Source code

High quality print and digital photographies for sale. Application Built using React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB.

- Authentification for user accounts : Bcryptis.
- Secured paiement via Stripe, Images storage via Cloudinary.
- Admin dashboard to manage orders, products and customers.

#### Community Network

View Website

Source code

Social App to connect outdoor sport addicts.

Application Built using React, Firebase, Leaflet, Bootstrap.

- Authentification & Database : Firebase, Firestore.
- Interactive map: Leaflet & GeoCode.
- User Interface: Customised Bootstrap.

More projects built from scratch:

Visit My Portfolio

# **EDUCATION / TRAINING**

Web Development Training: since OCTOBER 2019

OpenClassrooms, online courses, tutorials, official documentation...

General English Certificat: FEBRUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018

Intensive English courses B2+: Australian Pacific College, Brisbane # Humanitarian Logistic Bachelor: SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2014

Supply chain coordination training: Bioforce Institute - France

Migh School Certificate: JULY 2004

Civil Engineering Science: Gilbert Romme High School, France

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Technical Draftsman

OCTOBER 2017 - JANUARY 2018

Rector Lesage Group - Ravel, France

In charge of technical reviews in the engineering office of a factory for concrete element prefabrication.

- Established work plans on AutoCad software to create modular concrete floorings and beams.
- Evaluated and diagnosed customers requests, provided estimates, elements sizing and work plans.

Quality control Technician

OCTOBER 2016 - AUGUST 2017

CEMB - VICAT Cement Group - Fillinges, France

In charge of concrete quality control for a building materials laboratory after an internal training.

- Normalized and certified tests for all kind of concretes produced in 10 concrete production units.
- Analysed the test results, monitored, reported and followed up with customers.

Technical Salesman

MAY 2016 - OCTOBER 2016

L'Entrepôt du Bricolage - Annemasse, France

In charge of customer technical advisories in building materials trade.

- Order management for replenishment, improvement of the storage process and safety requirements.
- Humanitarian Logistic Manager

SEPTEMBER 2014 - MARCH 2016

Doctors Without Borders - Geneva, Switzerland

Construction Project Manager: Boga, Democratic Republic of Congo (3 months)

Monitored and implemented rehabilitations and construction for an hospital and several health centres.

- Supervised technical works, team management and progress follow-up.
- Ensured logistical aspects: budgeting, subcontracting, supply chain, purchase and storage process.
- Vaccination Logistic Manager: Kabalo, Democratic Republic of Congo (3 months)

Managed and planned logistic activities of an emergency vaccination campaign for a measle outbreak.

- Supervised logistic team to ensure transportation of medical teams, materials and cold chain.
- Scheduled 50 000 vaccinations with 160 team members within 4 weeks in over 50 villages.
- Hospital Logistic Manager: Leogane, Haiti (6 months)

Supervised logistics team & technical activities: transport, maintenance, team facilities, water, energy.

- In charge of the storage process and streamlining of materials excess with donations before closure.
- Developed and implemented a rehabilitation project for a partner hospital close to the 2010 earthquake's epicentre: masonry, water supply modernisation, refurbishment and electricity.

### Construction Supervisor

SEPTEMBER 2004 - APRIL 2013

BATICENTRE SARL - Cebazat, France

In charge of building site management for masonry, reinforced concrete and excavation operations.

- Supervised Team Leader of different building sites : management of 25 to 40 employees.
- Followed onsite activities to ensure smooth and efficient progress of projects.
- Ensured public relations in meetings to coordinate the diverse step of the constructions.
- Scheduled technical equipment requirements and planed equipment maintenance.
- Provided an efficient supply chain for materials and managed storage processes.
- Assessed work quality to ensure that the terms of reference and safety requirements are respected.
- Evaluated proposals, achieved estimates and quantified needs for new projects and public tenders.
- Established work plans to report technical aspects of the building sites.

# VOLUNTEERING

#### 

OCTOBER 2013 - JUNE 2014

ARIMC Association - Lyon, France

Project with a participatory approach helping an association supporting people with disabilities.

- Design, implementation and activities management of a shared garden for people with disabilities.
- Creation and manufacturing of gardening tables adapted for people in wheelchairs.
- Established work plans and reported building instructions to extend this project for a retirement home.

# KEY ACHIEVEMENTS & SOFT SKILLS

**TEAM WORKS** 

PROGRAMMING

**ADAPTABILITY** 

**MULTI TASKING** 

PROBLEM SOLVING

TEAM LEADING

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

CAPACITY TO LEARN

WORK UNDER PRESSURE

### PERSONAL INTERESTS

CODING

FAMILY

PARAGLIDING

**TECHNOLOGIES** 

PHOTOGRAPHY

SKI TOURING

**INTERNET** 

TRAVEL

SCUBA DIVING

### REFEREES

#### Alex SHAW

Tea Cup Cottage

Executive Director

alex@tea-cupcottage.com

+61 409 896 311

#### Rebecca ANDERSON

Doctors Without Borders
Project Medical Referent
randelallana@gmail.com
+41 766 077 523